Guide to the University of Pittsburgh Archives Audio Recordings Collection, 1950-2000 UA.Audio
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Administration, 1950-2000; III.
  - Staff Meetings, 1956-1997; 1.
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library), April 18, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 87)
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library), May 23, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 88)
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library) -, November 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 89)
    - Staff Advisory Committee on Policy (Library), Febraury 21, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 10, Cassette 84)
    - Open Hearing on the University Financial Crisis - Conducted by Cliff Cooper, Scott Baum, Dave Tiernan, John Seidman, Welsey Posvar, Henry Nicolas, Febraury 18, 1970; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 15, Reel 177)
    - Senate Library Meeting, November 6, 1972; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 24, Reel 273)
    - Senior Administrator's Conference, June 23, 1988; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 293)
    - Faculty Seminar: Arts and Hazards of Appearing on Public Media, March 25, 1982; 1 cassette_tape (Box 12, Cassette 140)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chancellor Posvar, September 15, 1976; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 112)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chancellor Posvar, 1981; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 13, Cassette 147)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chancellor Posvar, 1977; 1 cassette_tape (Box 14, Cassette 157)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chancellor Posvar, 1978; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 14, Cassette 158)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chancellor Posvar, 1979; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 14, Cassette 159)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chancellor Posvar, 1980; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 14, Cassette 160)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chacncellor Posvar, September 2, 1983; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 14, Cassette 167)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chancellor Posvar, November 24 1986; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 14, Cassette 277)
    - New Faculty Orientation - Chancellor Posvar, October 1, 1987; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 27, Cassette 285)
    - Emergency Medical Center Luncheon, November 1, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 126)
    - Lakeview Meeting, 1981; 7 cassette_tapes (Box 16, Cassette 188)
    - Pittsburgh Bicentennial Joint Committee, 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 17, Reel 200A)
    - Milltown Plenary Session, May 6, 1988; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 315)
    - University Senate's Plenary Session - "Pitt in Pittsburgh and Pennsylvania: Perils and Possibilities", October 16, 1997; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 324-325)
    - Senate Council, October 16, 1984; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 315-316)
  - Speeches/Lectures, 1957-1978; 2.
    This subseries contains 19 audio recordings of speeches given by faculty members at the University of Pittsburgh from 1957-1978. Most items are speeches given to third party businesses or events, highlighted by speeches given by Chancellor Wesley Posvar to the Allegheny County Ministerial Union and a speech by Posvar to the student body.
    - Chancellor Edward H. Litchfield Speech at New Kensington School, November 16, 1957; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 2, Reel 6)
    - Chancellor Litchfield Address at NAHRO Conference, April 18, 1961; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 27, Reel 290)
    - Chancellor Posvar's Speech at Meeting of Allegheny County Ministerial Union, November 10, 1969; 1 reel-to-reel 5" (Box 11, Item 121)
    - Litchfield speeches - Speaker Edward H. Litchfield, 1960
    - Chancellor Posvar - Pittsburgh Business Today Speech, December 7, 1970; 1 reel-to-reel 5"; 1 cassette tape (Box 7, Reel 60)
    - Bernadette Devlin Lecture - Carnegie Music Hall, February 15, 1971; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 28, Folder 318)
    - Community Housing Meeting - Chancellor Wesley Wentz Posvar Speech, February 23, 1972; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 14, Reel 155)
    - Asian Council Luncheon - Speech by Chancellor Posvar, September 18, 1973; 1 cassette_tape (Box 8, Cassette 78)
    - Introduction to the University - Speech by Dr. William Hung, March 9, 1973; 4 cassette_tapes (Box 11, Cassette 90)
    - Winchester-Thurston School Graduation - Capsule Biographies of Chancellor Posvar and his Wife, June 8, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 117)
    - Robert Wolke Presentation at Johnstown Conference, June 5, 1986; 1 cassette_tape (Box 24, Cassette 272)
    - Mill Towns: Despair, Hopes and Opportunities Conference - Speech by Chancellor Posvar, May 5-6, 1988; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 314)
    - 'Pitt in Pittsburgh and Pennsylvania: Perils and Possibilities" - University Senate's Plenary Session - Speakers Senator Melissa A. Hart and Rep. Frank Dermody, October 16, 1997; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 324-325)
    - Speech to Womens Association on the State of the University - Chancellor Posvar, May 3, 1972; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 8, Reel 63)
    - Chancellor Speech at Chatham, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 13, Reel 146)
    - Speech to Women's Association - Chancellor Posvar, 1972; 1 reel-to-reel 5" (Box 8, Reel 65)
    - Speech at Student Union - Chancellor Posvar, May 10, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 116)
    - American University Higher Education Core Cirriculum Seminar - Conducted by Chancellor Posvar, February 27, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 123)
    - Chancellor's Remarks at College of Arts and Sciences Undergraduate Advisor's Briefing - Chancellor Posvar, February 17, 1976; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 106)
    - Address To Middle States Association - Chancellor Litchfield, November 8, 1960; 1 reel-to-reel 5" (Box 15, Reel 168)
    - State of the University Address - Speaker - Edward H. Litchfield, October 14, 1959
    - Faculty address - Speaker - Edward H. Litchfield, March 13, 1957
    - Student Body Address - Speaker - Edward H. Litchfield, March 11, 1957
  - Joint Planning Seminars, 1958-1977; 3.
    This subseries contains 14 audio recordings of joint planning seminars at the University of Pittsburgh from 1958-1977. These items focus on the future planning of Pitt's goals moving into a modernized and urban future. Highlights include seminars discussing urban planning and the development of the urban environment.
    - "Various Aspects of Urban Planning" - Mr. Harvey Perloff, September 26, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 225)
    - "People of the Central City, of the Suburbs and of Exurbia" - Donald Bogue, October 3, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 226)
    - "Trends in the World Economy" - Conducted by Kurnets, February 23, 1977; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 223)
    - "Dynamics of a Free and Responsible Society" - Conducted by Dr. Milton Esman, November 10, 1955; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 21, Reel 227)
    - Joint Planning Seminar - Dr. Holmes Perkins, October 17, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 228)
    - Joint Planning Seminar - Dr. E. Hoover, October 24, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 229)
    - "The Evolving Metropolis" - Dr. R.L. Meir, Raymond A. Fisher, Thomas Stelson, October 31, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 230)
    - "The Politics of the Metropolis" - Fritz Gutheim, J. Steele Gow, Jr., James W. Knox, William Schulz, Jr., November 7, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 231)
    - "Urban Planning Past, Present and Future" - John T. Howard, Robert Weinberg, Park H. Martin, Paul Schwerlcher, November 14, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 232)
    - "Decision Making, Execution and the Planning Process" - Herbert A. Simon, Glenn Ferguson, C. Ronald Woods, November 21, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 233)
    - "Planning Organization and Activities within the Framework of Urban Government" - Henry Fagin, J, Keilcoff, December 5, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 234)
    - "Planning of Individual Services and Facilities in Relationship to General Planning for Community" - Dean Donald C. Stone, James A. Wodan, John J. Matthews, December 12, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 238)
    - "The Culture and Aesthetics of the Urban Community" - Norman Rice, January 9, 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 239)
    - "Urban Planning as a Field of Study" - Melville C. Braveh, Jr., January 15, 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 21, Reel 240)
- Student Life, 1950-2000; IV.
  This series contains audio recordings focused on detailing student life and events at the University of Pittsburgh from 1950-2000. Included within this series are student meetings, student centered events, and arts/entertainment conducted by students of the University. Notable highlights include numerous concert performances by the Heinz Chapel Choir.
  - Student Meetings/Administration, 1958-1959; 1.
    This subseries contains five audio recordings of student and student government meetings at the University of Pittsburgh from 1958-1959. Notable items in this subseries include discussion about implementing a trimester school plan, and the discussion around the principles of administration at Pitt.
    - Special Student Meeting - Dr. James Robinson, January ,7 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 22, Cassette 235)
    - Student Advisory Council - Discussion of Proposed Trimester Plan, January 7, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 53)
    - Special Student Meeting - Dr. Leland Burrows, January 7, 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 237)
    - Special Student Meeting - "Some Further Principles of Public Administration" - Donald C. Stone, Febraury 19, 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 241)
    - Special Student Meeting - "Principles of Public Administration - Donald C. Stone, March 10, 1959; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 242)
  - Student Events, 1970-1977; 2.
    This subseries contains seven audio recordings of student sponsored events at the University of Pittsburgh from 1970-1977. Notable entries in this subseries include a mass meeting of students in the Commons Room as well as addresses from the chancellor to parents and students during parents' weekend.
    - Variety Show, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 5"; Ekotape (Box 6, Reel 49)
    - Mass Meeting at Common Facilities Building, February 18, 1970; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 55)
    - Remarks at Parent's Reception - Commons Room - Chancellor Posvar, October 18, 1974; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 8, Reel 68)
    - Remarks at Parent's Reception - Chancellor Posvar, September 26, 1975; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 104)
    - Remarks at Parent's Reception - Chancellor Posvar, April 24, 1977; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 11, Cassette 114)
    - Address at Parent's Weekend - Chancellor Posvar, October 15, 1976; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 116)
    - Capital Campaign Kickoff, undated; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 296)
  - Concerts, 1954-1997; 3.
    This subseries contains 25 audio recordings of arts and entertainment events organized and performed by University of Pittsburgh students from 1954-1997. Most notably, this subseries contains numerous editions of concerts performed by the Heinz Chapel Choir during the 1990s.
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, December 10, 1990; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 326)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, October 20, 1991; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 327)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, December 8, 1991; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 328)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, Febraury 9, 1992; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 329)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, April 12, 1992; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 330)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, May 7, 1992; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 331)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, October 18, 1992; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 332)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, December 7, 1992; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 333)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, February 21, 1993; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 334)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, March 26, 1993; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 335)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, April 18, 1993; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 336)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, October 18, 1993; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 337)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, December 5, 1993; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 338)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, December 5, 1994; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 339)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, October 16, 1994; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 340)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, October 16, 1994; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 341)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, February 19, 1995; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 341)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, November 6, 1994; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 342)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, December 1995; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 343)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, April 14, 1996; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 344)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, December 3, 1996; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 345)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, April 13, 1997; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 346)
    - Heinz Chapel Choir Performance, undated; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 29, Cassette 347)
    - Russian Liturgical Music and Secular Selections, February 13, 1954; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 6, Reel 48)
    - 101st Fall Concert - Men's Glee Club, June 2, 1992; 1 cassette_tape (Box 29, Cassette 350)
    - Music for the Christmas Season, 1973
    - Hootenanny, 1963
- Media Events, 1950-2000; V.
  This series contains audio recordings of media events involving the University of Pittsburgh from 1950-2000. It comprises interviews, television programs, and radio programs which were focused on the University and its endeavors. Notable entries include WTAE and KDKA interviews with Chancellor Posvar.
  - Interviews, 1.
    This subseries contains ten audio recordings of interviews with Pitt faculty and staff. Spanning across Radio and Television, these interviews focus on the current events both internationally and in Pittsburgh. Notable interviews include a KDKA interview with Chancellor Posvar discussing financial problems in Pittsburgh.
    - An Interview with Leopold Stowkoski - Conducted by Harvey Pope, February 13, 1954; 1 reel-to-reel 7"; 1 cassette tape (Box 5, Reel 47)
    - Professor John Dewey 90th Birthday Interview - Conducted by Richard Hope, October 20, 1949; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 1, Reel 1)
    - KDKA Interview with Chancellor Posvar - Financial Problems, March 7, 1976; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 107)
    - Pitt and State Related Schools - Interview with Chancellor Posvar, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 5" (Box 19, Reel 208)
    - Interview with Helen Rush - Conducted by L. Jamison, 1983; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 24, Reel 275)
    - Interview with Chancellor Posvar - Conduckted by Ed Mullen, November 30, 1987; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 27, Reel 291)
    - Interview with Frank Zabrosky - Former Head of ASC - Conducted by Rebecca Abromitis, May 30, 1997; 4 cassette_tapes (Box 28, Cassette 320-323)
    - Interview with "Doc" Henry Clifford Carlson - Inverviewed by Tom R. Jones, Spring 1964; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Item 303)
    - The "Shaping of the Point" Reception - Interview with Chancellor Posvar and Mayor Caliguiri - Conducted by Robert C. Alberts, March 3, 1981; 1 cassette_tape (Box 29, Cassette 351)
    - Interview with Mary Sweeney - Conducted by Robert C. Alberts, March 31, 1981; 1 cassette_tape (Box 29, Cassette 352)
  - TV Programs, 1958-1977; 2.
    This subseries contains ten audio recordings focused on TV programs regarding the University of Pittsburgh and its dealings mainly in the City of Pittsburgh from 1958-1977. Notable entries include a series of programs conducted by the GSPIA, hosted by Eleanor Roosevelt, discussing the development of the world economy during the 1960's.
    - WTAE Interview with Chuck Jones on Watergate - Conducted by Colanelo, October 29, 1973; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 14, Reel 153)
    - WTAE Interview with Society of Women Engineers - Conducted by Pat Plants - 'New Dimensions in Education', December 5, 1973; 2 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 14, Reel 154)
    - WQED - Alternative Lifestyles Program, April 1975; 2 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 14, Reel 156)
    - Johnstown Administration Conference News Report - Ray Steele and Bob Wolke, 1983; 1 cassette_tape (Box 14, Cassette 166)
    - KDKA Story on Mellon Professorships $12 Million Dollar Grant, December 16, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel 5" (Box 15, Reel 170)
    - WPGH Programs on Pitt Libraries, March 22, 1973; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 7, Reel 69)
    - Chancellor Posvar on Roy Fox Show (KDKA) - Energy Conservation, October 31, 1977; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 11, Cassette 120)
    - KDKA "The Pennsylvania Way" Television Program, undated; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 18, Reel 201)
    - GSPIA Tape 37 - Eleanor Roosevelt 'Discussion of France and European Ogranization, March 4, 1962; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 24, Reel 261)
    - GSPIA Tape 43 - Eleanor Roosevelt - 'Future and Development of the Common Market', April 8, 1962; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 24, Reel 267)
  - School of Social Work Oral History, 3.
    - Interview with Nancy Lee, William McCollough, and Lenore Rainey - Conducted by Ken Kornick, March 8, 1993; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 304)
    - Interview with Nancy Lee - Conducted by Ken Kornick, March 8, 1993; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 305)
    - Interview with Barbara Shore, Moe Coleman, Dave Feehan - Conducted by Ken Kornick, March 8 ,1993; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 306)
    - Interview with Dave Feehan, Ruth Glick, Nancy Beck - Conducted by Ken Kornick, March 8, 1993; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 307)
    - Interview with Dr. Manuel Elmer, Dean David Epperson, Mildred Mink - Conducted by Ken Kornick, March 8, 1993; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 308)
    - Interview with Mildred Mink, Gail Hayman, Mandla Tshabalala - Conducted by Ken Kornick, March 8, 1993; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 309)
  - Radio Programs, 1976-1993; 4.
    This subseries contains four audio recordings of radio programs focusing on discussion of the University of Pittsburgh and its involvement in the region from 1976-1993. Highlights include the presentation of the Heinz Prize segment on WQED-FM.
    - KPFK Interview on FA Unions at UCLA and UCSD, October 16, 1976; 1 cassette_tape (Box 13, Cassette 150)
    - Heinz Prize Segment - Sunday Arts Magazine -WQED FM, April 13, 1986; 1 reel-to-reel 7" (Box 24, Reel 268)
    - Interview with Dr. Wesley Posvar - Re: South Africa on WTKN-AM, June 1993; 1 cassette_tape (Box 28, Cassette 312)
    - Tour and Critique of Black Artists Show - WQED-FM, November 13,1986-November 16,1986; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 30, Cassette 375)
- Lectures, 1956-1989; VI.
  This series includes audio recordings pertaining to lectures at the University of Pittsburgh from 1956-1989. Highlights of this series include a series of lectures on Women's Studies during the 1970's.
  - Seminar on Liberal Education for Adults, November 18-20, 1954; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 4, Reel 23)
  - Seminar: Graduate School of Public Health - Conducted by Dr. Kurtzmann, January 11, 1973; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 8, Reel 75)
  - Modern Philosophy: Class Discussions at the University of Pittsburgh, 1956; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 35)
  - Philosophy and Ethics, 1956; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 33)
  - Mentor Training Program - Conducted by S. Skewes, 1956; 6 reel-to-reel (Box 13, Reel 151)
  - Women's Issues - Affirmative Action at Pitt, 1969-1970; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 202A)
  - Women's Issues - Careers - Educational/Administrative, 1969-1970; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 202B)
  - Women's Issues - Prejudice in Psychology - Feminine Sex Role, 1969-1970; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 202C)
  - Women's Issues - Q-A from Women in News Media/Women Liberation, 1969-1970; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 202D)
  - Women's Issues - Welfare Right - Women in News Media, 1969-1970; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 202E)
  - Women's Issues - Abortion/Sexuality/Law, 1969-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 203)
  - Women's Issues - Women's Oppression at Pitt, 1969-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 203A)
  - Women's Issues - Abortion and Human Sexuality, 1969-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 203B)
  - Women's Issues - Sex Discrimination in Higher Education/Socialization, 1969-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 203C)
  - Women's Issues - Sexuality Freedoms/Sex Discrimination on the Job, 1969-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 203D)
  - Women's Issues - Women in Health Professions at Pitt, 1969-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 203E)
  - Women's Issues - Women in School of Engineering and Problems in Business Administration at Pitt, 1969-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 18, Reel 203F)
  - Women's Issues - Q and A, 1970-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 19, Reel 205)
  - Women's Issues - Nuclear War - Conducted by Dorothy Jones and Florence Kennedy, 1970-1971; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 19, Reel 206)
  - Learning to Use Microfilm, May 30, 1989; 1 cassette_tape (Box 27, Cassette 289)
  - Seminar 2000, November 22, 1972; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 11, Cassette 101)
  - Class Lectures - Dr. Flack (GSPIA), 1966; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 11, Reel 247)
  - Cultural Education Exchange Program - "Foreign Specialists" - Dr. Grundstein and Dr. Bayer, undated; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 22, Reel 239)
  - Seminar 208 - "Application of Motivation Psychology", March 9-10, 1959; 1 cassette_tape (Box 23, Item 248)
  - Pittsburgh As An Entity - Speaker - James Arthur Kehl, November 11, 1958
  - EDUCOM Second General Session, November 24, 1986; 1 cassette_tape (Box 24, Cassette 278)
  - Speech to Economics Club of Pittsburgh - Speakers- Dr. Ruben Schlesinger and Wesley W. Posvar, December 15, 1971
- Research Findings, 1952-1993; VII.
  This series includes audio recordings of research findings and presentations made at the University of Pittsburgh from 1952-1993. Highlights of this series include research by the Institute of Business and Economic Problems on the state of the changing international economy.
  - Institute of Business and Economic Problems - Unknown Speaker, November 5, 1957; 2 reel-to-reel (Box 4, Reel 24)
  - Institute of Business and Economic Problems - Small Business Manufacturers, 1952; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 36)
  - IoBEP - Scientific Research for Men's Products, 1957; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 34)
  - IoBEP - Methods of Managing, October 28, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 42)
  - IoBEP - Business Failures and Distress Loans, 1957; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 41)
  - IoBEP - Cardinal Rules for the Successful Operation of Business, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 40)
  - IoBEP - Industrial Credit Organizations on State and Local Levels, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 39)
  - IoBEP - Legal Aspects of Corporations, 1957; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 5, Reel 38)
  - IoBEP - Business and Banking Credit Organizations, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 6, Reel 43)
  - IoBEP - Financing Indistrial Development Projects, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 6, Reel 44)
  - IoBEP - Urban Planning and Re-Development Programs, 1958; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 6, Reel 45)
  - UCIS/DIALOG System Reception, October 30, 1978; 1 cassette_tape (Box 11, Cassette 125)
  - Research Workshop, 1983; 2 cassette_tapes (Box 14, Cassette 163)
  - Do Women Dare?, September 15, 1969; 2 reel-to-reel (Box 19, Reel 210)
  - Multinational Trade Negotations - Conducted by Jeza Fekete Kerty, January 19, 1977; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 20, Reel 214)
  - Changing Patterns in International Trade - Conducted by Robert Baldrim, January 26, 1977; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 20, Reel 215)
  - International Independence - Conducted by Thomas Willett, February 9, 1977; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 20, Reel 216)
  - The International Monetary System - Conducted by Soloman, March 2, 1977; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 20, Reel 217)
  - International Investment the Multi-National Corporation - Conducted by Blake, March 9, 1977; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 20, Reel 218)